<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Weeks on Empirical reporting</title>
    <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Weeks on Empirical reporting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introductions</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week01-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week01-1/</guid>
      <description>Maybe stories are just data with a soul
 Brené Brown   I’ll use this structure to lay out weely agendas, upcoming deadlines, readings, tutorials and more. The full assignments are in Canvas in the modules by month.
Unless I suggest otherwise, you’re expected to have done more than just skimmed through or reviewed the material. You should read, watch or listen closely and try to follow along on all of the tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The journalistic method</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week01-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week01-2/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a bit of writing advice I often share with students: engineers don’t look at a bridge the same way pedestrians or drivers do. The former understand the bridge as a language of angles and load bearing structures. Writers should read books in that same way.
&amp;mdash; jelani cobb (@jelani9) December 20, 2021  Agenda  Discussion: Empirical reporting and the journalistic method Lab: Reading the data-driven story  Upcoming deadlines Friday, 1/13</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining data</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week02-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week02-1/</guid>
      <description>data /ˈdeɪ.tə/ :
 information in an electronic form that can be stored and used by a computer*, or information, especially facts or numbers, collected to be examined and considered and used to help decision-making  Cambridge Dictionary -- almost*  * in reverse order
Some of this may feel abstract to you in the beginning but it will become more concrete as you start tackling datasets.
Agenda We have two days&#39; worth of work to do in only one class this week because of the MLK holiday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spreadsheet review I </title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week03-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week03-1/</guid>
      <description>Agenda  Discuss Census homework Lab: Reconstructing a Census story Demo: Pivot tables and grouping  Upcoming deadlines Sunday, 1/23
 Census assignment from boot camp  Friday, 1/28
 From filters to pivot tables using Notice of Claims data (I hope to finish this in the lab, but it might go a little long. You have seen this data system before in our warmup life of a dataset lab.)  Sunday, 1/30</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spreadsheet review II</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week03-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week03-2/</guid>
      <description>Agenda  Discuss reading Lab: Phoenix notice of claims data (Details here)  Upcoming deadlines Friday, 1/28
 Notice of Claims filter and pivot table (I hope to finish this in the lab, but it might go a little long. It&amp;rsquo;s good practice for this weekend&amp;rsquo;s test anyway)  Sunday, 1/30
 Spreadsheet assessment . This won&amp;rsquo;t be hard if you&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping up. You don&amp;rsquo;t even turn in a spreadsheet!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to programming with R</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week04-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week04-1/</guid>
      <description>For the next couple of weeks, it may seem that we&amp;rsquo;ve left the world of reporting and investigative journalism. Most of your work and reading is focused on a getting you started in a programming language without interruption.
Generally, each day will go sort of like this:
 We&amp;rsquo;ll go over the work from the previous class, and probably have a lab. I&amp;rsquo;ll introduce the new material in a demo, which you can follow along with (or not) You&amp;rsquo;ll then do after-class reading, which will make more sense once you&amp;rsquo;ve seen it in action.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with R and R Markdown</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week04-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week04-2/</guid>
      <description>Agenda  Create your first markdown document An introduction to (some of) the verbs of the Tidyverse using Billboard top 100 hits.  Upcoming deadlines Wednesday 2/2
 Markdown lab  Sunday 2/6
 Billboard Top 100 introductory tutorial. Do the after-class reading before you tackle this. Get as far as you can in 3-4 hours of dedicated work. This exercise will give me guidance on where to spend our time, so it&amp;rsquo;s more important that you try to do this on your own than it is that you get the &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; answer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going further with tidyverse verbs</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week05/</guid>
      <description>This marks the beginning of collapsing each week&amp;rsquo;s work into one page on this website.
This week, we&amp;rsquo;ll go over some details of how to use the most common five verbs: select, arrange, mutate, summarise, group_by, and filter using a data source more likely to yield interesting stories: The Paycheck Protection Program loans for businesses and projects in Arizona.
EDIT: I changed the details of what we&amp;rsquo;re doing on Wednesday, when we&amp;rsquo;ll look closer at the filter verb and get an introduction to filtering without an exact match.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verbs in depth part 2: Group, mutate, join</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week06/</guid>
      <description>This is our last week of basic verbs. With select, arrange, filter, summarise, group_by and now join , you&amp;rsquo;ll have most of what you need to analyze data in R! Next week we&amp;rsquo;ll start working to put it all into practice in a warm-up story memo project, and you&amp;rsquo;ll start seeing how to make your markdowns and data readable.
Agenda Monday Walkthrough on mutate and group_by/summarise. You&amp;rsquo;ll do the teaching!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regular expressions, tables and snippets</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week08/</guid>
      <description>Agenda Monday   More on regular expressions - A lab that helps you understand more about what you are doing in the str_detect function in filtering and mutating - some of this will not be in R, but will be on a website that helps you write the patterns.
  Open lab to work on getting started on your replication project. While you may work together in labs to help one another get started, this is intended as an individual, not a team, project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualization as a reporting tool</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week09/</guid>
      <description>From now on, you won&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of homework - most of your work will be either in-class labs or projects on your own, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of preparation for any classes. I&amp;rsquo;ll start listing in the agenda links to any presentations or other materials we use in class.
Agenda Monday 3/14   Presentation on visualization as a reporting tool
  Knight Center&amp;rsquo;s online course on visualization from Alberto Cairo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>... and we&#39;re almost done!</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week10/</guid>
      <description>Upcoming deadlines Friday 4/8
 Your database design for the &amp;ldquo;building a database&amp;rdquo; assignment. Turn in a link to an Airtable, and be sure you&amp;rsquo;ve shared it with me (shcohen1@asu.edu)  Sunday 4/10
 First update to story memo  Sunday 4/17
 Second update to story memo  Sunday 4/24
 Final version of story memo and documentation  Friday 5/4
 Explainer  Reading and agenda by class date Monday, April 4   Textbook chapter : &amp;ldquo;Building your own database&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
