<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Weeks on Empirical reporting</title>
    <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Weeks on Empirical reporting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introductions</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week01-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week01-1/</guid>
      <description>Maybe stories are just data with a soul
 Brené Brown   I’ll use this structure to lay out weely agendas, upcoming deadlines, readings, tutorials and more. The full assignments are in Canvas, listed under modules by month.
Unless I suggest otherwise, you’re expected to have done more than just skimmed through or reviewed the material. You should read, watch or listen closely and try to follow along on all of the tutorials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The journalistic method</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week01-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week01-2/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a bit of writing advice I often share with students: engineers don’t look at a bridge the same way pedestrians or drivers do. The former understand the bridge as a language of angles and load bearing structures. Writers should read books in that same way.
&amp;mdash; jelani cobb (@jelani9) December 20, 2021  Agenda  Discussion: Empirical reporting and the journalistic method Lab: Reading the data-driven story  Upcoming deadlines Friday, 1/13</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining data</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week02-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week02-1/</guid>
      <description>data /ˈdeɪ.tə/ :
 information in an electronic form that can be stored and used by a computer*, or information, especially facts or numbers, collected to be examined and considered and used to help decision-making  Cambridge Dictionary   * in reverse order
Some of this may feel abstract to you in the beginning but it will become more important as you start tackling datasets.
Agenda We have two days&#39; worth of work to do in only one class this week because of the MLK holiday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spreadsheet review I </title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week03-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week03-1/</guid>
      <description>Agenda  Discuss Census homework Re-introducing the Notice of Claims data Demo: Pivot tables and grouping Lab: Reconstructing a Census story  Upcoming deadlines Sunday, 1/23
 Refresher from boot camp  Friday, 1/28
 Notice of Claims filter and pivot table (I hope to finish this in the lab, but it might go a little long)  Sunday, 1/30
 Spreadsheet assessment . If you&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping up, this won&amp;rsquo;t be hard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spreadsheet review II</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week03-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/weeks/week03-2/</guid>
      <description>Agenda  Discuss reading Lab: Phoenix notice of claims data (Details here)  Upcoming deadlines Friday, 1/28
 Notice of Claims filter and pivot table (I hope to finish this in the lab, but it might go a little long. It&amp;rsquo;s good practice for this weekend&amp;rsquo;s test anyway)  Sunday, 1/30
 Spreadsheet assessment . This won&amp;rsquo;t be hard if you&amp;rsquo;ve been keeping up. You don&amp;rsquo;t even turn in a spreadsheet!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
