<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Reporting on Empirical reporting</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Reporting on Empirical reporting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Introductions</title>
      <link>/weeks/week01-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weeks/week01-1/</guid>
      <description>A full list of the agenda, upcoming due dates and preparation required for the first day of class</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The journalistic method</title>
      <link>/weeks/week01-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weeks/week01-2/</guid>
      <description>Here’s a bit of writing advice I often share with students: engineers don’t look at a bridge the same way pedestrians or drivers do. The former understand the bridge as a language of angles and load bearing structures. Writers should read books in that same way.
&amp;mdash; jelani cobb (@jelani9) December 20, 2021  Agenda  Discussion: Empirical reporting and the journalistic method Lab: Reading the data-driven story  Upcoming deadlines Friday, 1/13</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empirical Reporting</title>
      <link>/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: Sorry, you just have to read it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining data</title>
      <link>/weeks/week02-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weeks/week02-1/</guid>
      <description>data /ˈdeɪ.tə/ :
 information in an electronic form that can be stored and used by a computer, or information, especially facts or numbers, collected to be examined and considered and used to help decision-making  Cambridge Dictionary   (I reversed the order of these!)
Agenda  Reviewing what is &amp;ldquo;data&amp;rdquo;? Lab - The life of a dataset warmup Replication in data journalism and the data diary  Upcoming deadlines Friday 1/21</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preliminary weekly schedule</title>
      <link>/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 13:21:30 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/schedule/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: Sorry, you just have to read it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spreadsheet refresher</title>
      <link>/weeks/week03-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weeks/week03-1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> </title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 13:19:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Sarah Cohen  This is the poorly named website for my data journalism course at Arizona State University’s Cronkite School. It focuses on documents and data reporting in investigations.
I began teaching in Arizona in 2018 as the Knight Chair in Journalism. This is my second tour as a Knight chair – the first was at Duke University’s Sanford School of Public Policy, from 2009 to 2012.
I’ve been a reporter and editor for most of my career, starting out as a beat reporter in Florida covering health care, workplace issues and the local economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ready, set...</title>
      <link>/updates/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/updates/welcome/</guid>
      <description>This site will give you most of what you need, but whenever there is a conflict between Canvas and this site, Canvas is the right one. Please alert me to conflicts, broken links or other mechanical issues as soon as possible via Slack. (Posting in #dj-sos Slack channel will ensure that everyone gets the answer, but you don’t have to. )
I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting here from time to time with important announcements, but you&amp;rsquo;ll hear everything first in Slack.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
