<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coursedocs on Empirical reporting</title>
    <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/coursedocs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coursedocs on Empirical reporting</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/coursedocs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build your own database</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/coursedocs/builddb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/coursedocs/builddb/</guid>
      <description>This is an assignment that challenges you to build a database out of documents or individual items that you collect yourself. I&amp;rsquo;m still deciding which documents to use for this, and will update it after Spring Break. We&amp;rsquo;ll do it partly in a lab, and then you&amp;rsquo;ll finish it up yourself in April.
If you have documents you want me to consider for this, please let me know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mini-project: Explainer</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/coursedocs/explainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/coursedocs/explainer/</guid>
      <description>This assignment involves identifying one thing related to class that you’d like to apply or understand better, and produce an explainer around it. This could be a technique in R that you found confusing, something you decided to teach yourself because you found an interesting example, or a dataset that we didn’t really review in class that you’d like to explore. Run the idea by me before you put too much work into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Replication project details </title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/coursedocs/replication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/coursedocs/replication/</guid>
      <description>The aim of this project is to identify and replicate the major findings from a story or series. It will be completed in three parts, which altogether accounts for 15 percent of your final grade.
How it works You&amp;rsquo;ll study the story and identify the key facts that derived from the primary dataset used. Then, over the course of a couple of weeks, you&amp;rsquo;ll try to replicate those findings using the R skills you will be learning in class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Story memo details</title>
      <link>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/coursedocs/memo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cronkitedata.github.io/dataj/coursedocs/memo/</guid>
      <description>This project makes up 15 percent of your final grade. It involves analyzing a dataset that contains records that would be of interest to a story or feature.
Key deadlines:
March 27: A three paragraph description of your proposed story memo
April 11: Update #1 - your hypotheses and first stabs at the data
April 17 : Update #2: Your nut graf and b-matter
April 24: Final story memo and documentation .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
